Beth Hobson

15114 North County Road 3215 Pauls Valley, OK 73075 (405)207-8778 • bhobsonphoto@gmail.com www.bhobsonphoto.com

As a young photographer I used my internship that I completed as a sophomore at the University of Oklahoma to help establish my own photography business. I started out as an artist with a hobby in nature photography. In less than four years I've not only taken nature photos, but I have also worked in many other genres of photography including: architectural, black and white, macro, portraits, products, and still life just to name a few. My photography was also featured in December 2012's issue of Oklahoma Magazine among 29 other photographers in Oklahoma selected by the Golding Group, and Scissortail Creative for their creative endeavor entitled 30 Days 30 Photographers.

In my previous positions of work that I held while I was a high school student, I maintained an above 3.0 GPA, carried nine hours of class work, played soccer, showed and helped train horses. It required determination, diligence, passion and understanding from the very beginning. I used the skills that I learned to help drive myself as I graduated a year early from high school.

It is my goal to continue using these skills that I applied to my high school and now my university work that I just completed in December of 2013 as I continue to accomplish my goals and set myself apart from any other young photographers my age.

I hope that you will please consider the talent that I could offer to your organization. Thank you for your time. I am excited about the prospect of beginning a new journey.

Yours truly,

Beth Hobson

Enclosure: Resume

Beth Hobson

15114 North County Road 3215 Pauls Valley, OK 73075 (405)207-8778 • bhobsonphoto@gmail.com www.bhobsonphoto.com

OBJECTIVE

A position with the capabilities of using media and criminal justice skills.

SKILLS

- **Software:** Adobe Acrobat, Adobe Photoshop, Apple Pages, Apple iWeb, Apple Final Cut Express, Corel Paint Shop Pro, Magicx Movie Edit Pro, Microsoft Word, Microsoft PowerPoint, Windows Movie Maker, Windows Publisher, and some Microsoft Access, and Outlook.
- Photography: 35mm, some Medium Format, Digital Shooting, Color Correction, Editing, Photo Manipulation and Retouching, Scanning, and some Studio Lighting.
- Graphic Design/Web Design/Video Production/Editing: Six years of total experience.

I have also directed, scripted, transferred and edited videos for almost five years.

• Writing: Articles, Novels, Poems, Short Stories, and Reviews.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

• Beth H. Photography *Photographer/Editor*

Oklahoma 2008-Present

In late 2008, I started taking photos with a new idea in mind, to transform my hobby into a profession. I edit, manipulate, direct and take photos for a variety of clients. I shoot studio, outdoors and on location. My portfolio is available.

• Dr. Bruce Varner O.D. 100 Maxwell Drive, Pauls Valley, OK Maintenance Work/Office Cleaning 2004-2012

I was responsible for the upkeep of the building. The yard needed to be kept free of trash and the office's interior needed to be maintained each weekend.

Pelco Products, Inc Intern/Photographer/Editor

320 W. 18th, Edmond, OK June 2009

I was required to photograph Pelco's products out in the field as well as in a self-created studio. All of Pelco's products had to be pulled off of the shelf and photographed and replaced. I was also required to spend one day every week in the editing bay. I learned from their marketing and advertising director how to apply the knowledge that I've gained thus far to create photos that were used for advertisements, marketing, public relations, and website use for the company.

EDUCATION

University of Oklahoma

Norman, OK

Bachelor of Arts in Planned Program with emphasis in Media Coverage of Social Issues and a minor in Sociology.

Graduated: December 2013

- -Deans Honor Roll
- -3.46 Cumulative GPA at OU, 3.34 GPA Combined
- -4.0 GPA by the end of second full year at the Gaylord College of Mass Communication before transferring to the College of Arts and Science.
- -General Education Classes, major and minor classes.
- Selected by advisor due to high GPA to carry the Planned Program's Convocation Banner

Related Coursework: Crime and the Media Independent Study, Sociology of Family, Sociology of Deviance, Criminology, Introduction to Criminal Justice, Intro to Forensic Science, Photography Theory and Criticism, Criminal Investigation, Cyberspace Security, Sociology of Violence, The System of Criminal Justice, Writing for the Mass Media, Intro to Advertising, Intro to Mass Media, Media Equipment, Voice & Diction for Non-Majors, Public Speaking, Art Humanities I, Intro to Sociology, and American Federal Government.

• East Central University

Ada, OK

-Deans Honor Roll

2006-Summer 2008 and Fall 2009

- -Maintained a 3.0 Cumulative GPA
- -General Education Classes and a couple Intro classes into Media.

Elmore City- Pernell High School and University of Oklahoma Elmore-City, OK

- -Governor's and Superintendent Honor Rolls every year 2003-2005
- -Graduated as a Junior
- -Two years High School Newspaper
- -Maintained a 3.0+ GPA
- -Graduated top twenty percent of class
- -General Diploma
- -Took two classes through OU's independent study program

Pauls Valley High School

Pauls Valley, OK

2002

-Governor's and Superintendent Honor Roll

-Maintained a 3.0+ GPA

COMMUNITY AND HIGH-SCHOOL INVOLVEMENT

• Member or Participant of:

The National Appaloosa Horse Club: 4 and a half years

The National Appaloosa Youth Horse Club: 4 and a half years

Oklahoma Appaloosa Horse Club: 4 and a half years

Oklahoma Appaloosa Youth Horse Club: 4 and a half years

Dal-Worth Appaloosa Horse Club: 4 and a half years

Oklahoma 4-H: 4 and a half years

High School Newspaper: 2 years

Pauls Valley Youth Soccer League: Approximately 10 years

Pauls Valley Youth Basketball League: Approximately 6 years

Harvey Stevens Training Center: Worked the summer of 2002 with him taking care of show horses.

30 Days 30 Photos 30 Photographers (30/30/30) presented by the Golding Group, Scissortail Creative, and Oklahoma Magazine 2012.

• Photography Published in:

2012 December Issue of Oklahoma Magazine for 30 Days 30 Photos 30 Photographers.